proko.com 2019-12-02

# Privacy Policy | Proko

## Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that this Website collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies, Usage Data, email address, first name, website, last name, username and password.

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.  
Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using this Website.  
Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by this Website is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for this Website to provide its services. In cases where this Website specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service.  
Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.  
Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this Website or by the owners of third-party services used by this Website serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy, if available.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through this Website and confirm that they have the third party’s consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

* * *

## Mode and place of processing the Data

**Methods of processing**  
The Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Owner, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of this Website (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Owner at any time.

**Legal basis of processing**  
The Owner may process Personal Data relating to Users if one of the following applies:

Users have given their consent for one or more specific purposes. Note: Under some legislations the Owner may be allowed to process Personal Data until the User objects to such processing (“opt-out”), without having to rely on consent or any other of the following legal bases. This, however, does not apply, whenever the processing of Personal Data is subject to European data protection law;  
provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an agreement with the User and/or for any pre-contractual obligations thereof;  
processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Owner is subject;  
processing is related to a task that is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Owner;  
processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner or by a third party.  
In any case, the Owner will gladly help to clarify the specific legal basis that applies to the processing, and in particular whether the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract.

**Place**  
The Data is processed at the Owner’s operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.

Depending on the User’s location, data transfers may involve transferring the User’s Data to a country other than their own. To find out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users can check the section containing details about the processing of Personal Data.

Users are also entitled to learn about the legal basis of Data transfers to a country outside the European Union or to any international organization governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about the security measures taken by the Owner to safeguard their Data.

If any such transfer takes place, Users can find out more by checking the relevant sections of this document or inquire with the Owner using the information provided in the contact section.

**Retention time**  
Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for.

Therefore:

* Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance of a contract between the Owner and the User shall be retained until such contract has been fully performed.
* Personal Data collected for the purposes of the Owner’s legitimate interests shall be retained as long as needed to fulfill such purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner within the relevant sections of this document or by contacting the Owner.

The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever the User has given consent to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, the Owner may be obliged to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to do so for the performance of a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.

Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right to access, the right to erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after expiration of the retention period.

* * *

## The purposes of processing

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its Services, as well as for the following purposes: Analytics, Contacting the User, Managing contacts and sending messages, Displaying content from external platforms, Handling payments, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Commercial affiliation, Content commenting, Registration and authentication, Remarketing and behavioral targeting and SPAM protection.

Users can find further detailed information about such purposes of processing and about the specific Personal Data used for each purpose in the respective sections of this document.

* * *

## Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

**Google Analytics (Google Inc.)**  
Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Website, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.  
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

**WordPress Stats (Automattic Inc.)**  
Wordpress Stats is an analytics service provided by Automattic Inc.  
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/).

**Facebook Ads conversion tracking (Facebook, Inc.)**  
Facebook Ads conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Facebook, Inc. that connects data from the Facebook advertising network with actions performed on this Website.  
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant.

### Commercial Affiliation

This type of service allows this Website to display advertisements for third-party products or services. Ads can be displayed either as advertising links or as banners using various kinds of graphics.  
Clicks on the icon or banner posted on the Application are tracked by the third-party services listed below, and are shared with this Website.  
For details of which data are collected, please refer to the privacy policy of each service.

**Amazon Affiliation (Amazon)**  
Amazon Affiliation is a commercial affiliation service provided by Amazon.com Inc.  
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=hp_rel_topic?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496).

**iDevAffiliate (iDevDirect LLC)**  
iDevAffiliate is a commercial affiliation service provided by iDevDirect LLC.  
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.idevdirect.com/policies.php).

### Mailing List or Newsletter (This Website)

By registering on the mailing list or for the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning this Website. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to this Website or after making a purchase. Personal Data collected: email address and first name.

**Managing contacts and sending messages**

This type of services makes it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User.  
These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.

**MailChimp (The Rocket Science Group, LLC.)**  
MailChimp is an email address management and message sending service provided by The Rocket Science Group, LLC.  
Personal Data collected: first name, email address.

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/).

**CAN SPAM Act**

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

**We collect your email address in order to:**

• Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.  
• Process orders and to send information and updates pertaining to orders  
• We may also send you additional information related to your product and/or service.  
• Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after the original transaction has occurred

**To be accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:**

• NOT use false, or misleading subjects or email addresses  
• Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way  
• Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters  
• Monitor third party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.  
• Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly  
• Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email

**If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can**

• Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email.

### Displaying Content from External Services

This type of services allows you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this Website and interact with them.  
This type of service might still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

**Gravatar (Automattic Inc.)**  
Gravatar is an image visualization service provided by Automattic Inc. that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.  
Please note that if Gravatar images are used for comment forms, the commenter’s email address or parts of it may be sent to Gravatar – even if the commenter has not signed up for that service.  
Personal Data collected: email address and Usage Data.

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/).

**Vimeo video (Vimeo, LLC)**  
Vimeo is a video content visualization service provided by Vimeo, LLC that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.  
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://vimeo.com/privacy).

**YouTube video**  
YouTube is a video content visualization service provided by Google that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.  
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.youtube.com/yt/about/policies/).

### Content Commenting

Content commenting services allow Users to make and publish their comments on the contents of this Website.  
Depending on the settings chosen by the Owner, Users may also leave anonymous comments. If there is an email address among the Personal Data provided by the User, it may be used to send notifications of comments on the same content. Users are responsible for the content of their own comments.  
If a content commenting service provided by third parties is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the comment service is installed, even when Users do not use the content commenting service.

**Comment system managed directly (this Website)**  
This Website has its own internal content comment system.  
Personal Data collected: email address, first name and website.

### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

This type of service allows interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this Website. The interaction and information obtained through this Website are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network. This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

**AddThis (Addthis Inc.)**  
AddThis is a service provided by Clearspring Technologies Inc., which displays a widget that allows interaction with social networks and external platforms as well as sharing the contents of this Website.  
Depending on the configuration, this service can display widgets belonging to third parties such as the managers of social networks where interactions are shared. In this case, also the third parties that provide the widget will be informed of interactions and Usage Data on the pages where this service is installed.  
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy).

### Handling Payments

Payment processing services enable this Website to process payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means. To ensure greater security, this Website shares only the information necessary to execute the transaction with the financial intermediaries handling the transaction.  
Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails containing invoices or notifications concerning the payment.

**PayPal (PayPal Inc.)**  
PayPal is a payment service provided by PayPal Inc., which allows Users to make online payments using their PayPal credentials.  
Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the [privacy policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) of the service.

**Stripe (Stripe Inc)**  
Stripe is a payment service provided by Stripe Inc.  
Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/terms/US). Privacy Shield participant.

**Selling Goods and Services online**  
The Personal Data collected are used to provide the User with services or to sell goods, including payment and possible delivery.  
The Personal Data collected to complete the payment may include the credit card, the bank account used for the transfer, or any other means of payment envisaged. The kind of Data collected by this Website depends on the payment system used. This Website does not store the credit card or banking information of its Users.

### Registration and authentication

By registering or authenticating, Users allow this Website to identify them and give them access to dedicated services.  
Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services. In this case, this Website will be able to access some Data, stored by these third-party services, for registration or identification purposes.

**Direct registration (this Website)**  
The User registers by filling out the registration form and providing the Personal Data directly to this Website.  
Personal Data collected: email address, first name, last name, password and username.

### SPAM protection

This type of service analyzes the traffic of this Website, potentially containing Users’ Personal Data, with the purpose of filtering it from parts of traffic, messages and content that are recognized as SPAM.

**Akismet (Automattic Inc.)**  
Akismet is a SPAM protection service provided by Automattic Inc.  
Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/).

### Remarketing and behavioral targeting

This type of service allows this Website and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of this Website by the User.  
This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity.  
In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service’s use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

**Facebook Custom Audience (Facebook, Inc.)**  
Facebook Custom Audience is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Facebook, Inc. that connects the activity of this Website with the Facebook advertising network.  
Personal Data collected: Cookies and email address.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/). Privacy Shield participant.

**Facebook Remarketing (Facebook, Inc.)**  
Facebook Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Facebook, Inc. that connects the activity of this Website with the Facebook advertising network.  
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/). Privacy Shield participant.

**Remarketing through Google Analytics for Display Advertising (Google Inc.)**  
Google Analytics for Display Advertising is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the tracking activity performed by Google Analytics and its Cookies with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.  
Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout). Privacy Shield participant.

* * *

## The rights of Users

Users may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by the Owner.

In particular, Users have the right to do the following:

* **Withdraw their consent at any time.** Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to the processing of their Personal Data.
* **Object to processing of their Data.** Users have the right to object to the processing of their Data if the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent. Further details are provided in the dedicated section below.
* **Access their Data.** Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the Owner, obtain disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing processing.
* **Verify and seek rectification.** Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.
* **Restrict the processing of their Data.** Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to restrict the processing of their Data. In this case, the Owner will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it.
* **Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed.** Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to obtain the erasure of their Data from the Owner.
* **Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller.** Users have the right to receive their Data in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and, if technically feasible, to have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance. This provision is applicable provided that the Data is processed by automated means and that the processing is based on the User’s consent, on a contract which the User is part of or on pre-contractual obligations thereof.
* **Lodge a complaint.** Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority.

**Details about the right to object to processing**

Where Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority vested in the Owner or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner, Users may object to such processing by providing a ground related to their particular situation to justify the objection.

Users must know that, however, should their Personal Data be processed for direct marketing purposes, they can object to that processing at any time without providing any justification. To learn, whether the Owner is processing Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, Users may refer to the relevant sections of this document.

**How to exercise these rights**  
Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner through the contact details provided in this document. These requests can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed by the Owner as early as possible and always within one month.

* * *

## Cookie Policy

This Website uses Cookies. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

**We use cookies to:**

• Help remember and process the items in the shopping cart.  
• Understand and save user’s preferences for future visits.  
• Keep track of advertisements.  
• Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf.  
You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

**If users disable cookies in their browser** :

If you disable cookies off, some features will be disabled. It will turn off some of the features that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly.

However, you can still place orders, processing orders, login to member area, account management, by contacting customer service.

* * *

## Additional information about Data collection and processing

**Legal action**  
The User’s Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Website or the related Services.  
The User declares to be aware that the Owner may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.

**Additional information about User’s Personal Data**  
In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Website may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular Services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.

**System logs and maintenance**  
For operation and maintenance purposes, this Website and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with this Website (System logs) use other Personal Data (such as the IP Address) for this purpose.

**Information not contained in this policy**  
More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Owner at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.

**How “Do Not Track” requests are handled**  
We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**How we protect visitor information**

Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.  
We implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order to maintain the safety of your personal information.

All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. – See more at: http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf

**According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:**

Users can visit our site anonymously  
Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page, or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.  
Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’, and can be easily be found on the page specified above.  
Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:  
• On our Privacy Policy Page  
Users are able to change their personal information:  
• By emailing us  
• By logging in to their account

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation’s consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under 13.

**Fair Information Practices**

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

**In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:**

We will notify the users via email  
• Within 7 business days  
We will notify the users via in site notification  
• Within 7 business days  
We also agree to the individual redress principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or a government agency to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

**Changes to this privacy policy**  
The Owner reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page and possibly within this Website and/or – as far as technically and legally feasible – sending a notice to Users via any contact information available to the Owner. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. 

Should the changes affect processing activities performed on the basis of the User’s consent, the Owner shall collect new consent from the User, where required.

**Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

Proko LLC  
8963 Complex Dr Ste B  
San Diego, Ca 92123-1416  
United States  
support@proko.com

Last Edited on 2018-06-04

## Definitions and legal requests

**Personal Data (or Data)**  
Any information that directly, indirectly, or in connection with other information — including a personal identification number — allows for the identification or identifiability of a natural person.

**Usage Data**  
Information collected automatically through this Website (or third-party services employed in this Website), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use this Website, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server’s answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User’s IT environment.

**User**  
The individual using this Website who, unless otherwise specified, coincides with the Data Subject.

**Data Subject**  
The natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

**Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)**  
The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes Personal Data on behalf of the Controller, as described in this privacy policy.

**Data Controller (or Owner)**  
The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of Personal Data, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this Website. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of this Website.

**This Website (or this Application)**  
The means by which the Personal Data of the User is collected and processed.

**Service**  
The service provided by this Website as described in the relative terms (if available) and on this site/application.

**European Union (or EU)**  
Unless otherwise specified, all references made within this document to the European Union include all current member states to the European Union and the European Economic Area.

**Cookies**  
Small piece of data stored in the User’s device.

**Legal information**  
This privacy statement has been prepared based on provisions of multiple legislations, including Art. 13/14 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (General Data Protection Regulation).

This privacy policy relates solely to this Website, if not stated otherwise within this document.
